Pradnesh Mhatre

+91-9892873200 | pradnesh0729@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Profile

Summary

Seasoned Software Engineer with more than 6.5 years of experience specializing in backend development using Java, Spring Boot, and Microservices. Technically sound in designing and engineering distributed applications, optimizing performance, and leading critical initiatives. Looking forward to apply expertise in the enterprise-level systems and microservices architecture in a constantly evolving tech environment.

EDUCATION

Mumbai University Bachelor of Engineering Mumbai, MH

August 2014 - May 2018

EXPERIENCE

Senior Associate Technology L1

March 2022 – Present

Publicis Sapient

Pune, MH

- Working for the world's largest hotel chain, Marriott International as a channel side Lead Developer
- Instrumented revenue generating backend services on Marriott website's hotel booking journey that directly interact with the frontend components on the site making the systems 250% more product-interactive and 60-80% more performance-efficient compared to previous iterations
- Comprehensive experience in distributed backend application design and implementation using Reactive programming, Couchbase, NginX, AWS Elastic Kubernetes Service, Redhat OpenShift, Microservices patterns, and Performance Engineering
- Led the setup of NginX web server for Marriott's Bulgari hotel's booking path from scratch and supported Marriott's Phoenix project to be launched in multiple European and Asian countries as part of the localization project
- Proactively spearheaded the non-functional requirements (NFRs) like performance monitoring and scaling. Guided and mentored a team of 7 developers on hotel modify/cancel journeys on Marriott site
- Recognised for generating notable client impact and received appreciation by Product Management for adding value in technical solution designing

Lead Engineer

March 2021 - March 2022

HCL Technologies

Pune, MH

- Worked for a leading US-based international money transfer company, Western Union
- Orchestrated the re-architecture of backend modules in collaboration with the Experience Platform team, directly enhancing system performance, leading to improved customer satisfaction scores
- Engineered and resolved modules in transaction management, customer profile, authentication service
- Successfully implemented GraphQL with Netflix-DGS framework, applying test-driven development and resolving
- Partnered with Web Performance Optimization team to optimize the website content APIs through Akamai as content delivery network (CDN), this improved page performance by 75%

System Engineer

Tata Consultancy Services

June 2018 – March 2021

Mumbai, MH

- Began career working with a US-based online travel agency, Priceline.com
- Designed and delivered various back-office Java applications for client's finance department
- Collaborated on the maintenance and tech support of client's existing services, and processes
- Contributed to the financial vendor and customer reports generation services. On a daily basis, tens and hundreds of reports were generated by the Analytics Team

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages & Frameworks: Java, Spring Boot, Microservices, SQL/NoSQL, NginX Lua, Saga, Junit, GraphQL Tools: Git, DynaTrace, Splunk, Jmeter, Jenkins, Docker, AWS EKS, Redhat Openshift, Octant Libraries: Project Reactor, Spring Core and Cloud, Axon Framework, Mapstruct/Lombok, Apache Kafka, Mockito, Netflix DGS